Syed Muhammad Nouman

Date of Birth: 14 August 1984 **CNIC:** 44203-0381871-9

Address: G-1, 69/4, Bilal Heights Muslim League Quarters Nazimabad

Number 1, Karachi

Tel (Office): +92 21 35211098 Ext. 382 Mobile: +92 313-0242921 & +92 335-0031892

Email: syed syed786@hotmail.com

URL: https://www.linkedin.com/in/syed-muhammad-nouman-86b33723

Professional Summary

Proven as multi-disciplined, management skills and a major player in numerous operations and projects and implemented and developed new systems with cost constraints and best available resources.

I'm truly passionate about helping teams understand customers better and creating products and services that plaster silly grins on customers' faces whenever they engage with traditional and alternative touch-points. Have a diplomatic management style, whilst empowers, develops and encourages a self-development culture.

Having a diversified professional career, with more than 8 years, I have worked in different areas and have grown myself along with the organization. Highly experienced in

• Projects (SMS Banking, Utility Bill Payments, POS & Prepaid Commercial Program, Call Center & IVR, Internet Banking, EMV Project, Mobile App)

Experience

Team Lead & Senior Project Manager at First Women Bank limited

January 2017 - Present

Current Project EMV Upgrade

Project Management of vendor based ADC projects and Supervising of ADC Support Team.

EMV / Contact less Master Card Issuing.

EMV / Contact less PayPak Cards Issuing and Acquiring

Domestic EMV Acquiring.

Internet Banking upgrade on API

ISO message format Certification via 1-link

IBFT 3.0

Upgrade (Call Center & IVR, Internet Banking, ATMs, Cards)

MasterCard Stand-In project completed

Mobile App

Push & Pull SMS Service

Launched Banks first push and Pull SMS service, with its enablement customer stays updated with all debit and credit transactions via SMS alerts and can also pull balance and last five transactions of his/her Account.

Implementation of International Banking Solution

Launched Banks first IBAN system, leveraging customer to transfer funds from any part of the world into Banks IBAN account

Stability in Banks Middleware System

Brought stability in Banks existing Information System middleware and brought the system uptime to 100%

Implementation of Information System Dash board

Launched Banks first Dash Board in order to monitor the Banks Information System including transaction processing and system uptime.

FWBL Debit PayPak Card

Launched Banks first ever Debit Card to leverage customers, PayPak a local payment card scheme introduced by 1-Link and strongly backed by the regulatory, where card acceptance is not be limited to ATMs only and can be used at merchants for purchase transactions, and the purpose of introducing PayPak is to promote the local payment card scheme at a low cost footprint.

FWBL Debit MasterCard

In implementation phase, a robust and value added service of Debit Cards with greater convenience & competitive advantage through direct shopping, enhanced availability, higher limits & international acceptance of Debit Card Programs.

Page 1

CTI/IVR Contact Center & Phone Banking

In implementation phase, Self-service banking via Interactive voice response featured with TPIN and ATM PIN generation / validation, balance Inquiry, transition details, Funds Transfer, Cheque book request.

FWBL Internet / Electronic Banking Solution

In implementation phase, one of the most convenient and easily accessible services, Internet Banking has played a pivotal role how banking operates altogether. Now, the customer does not have to visit the branch, stand in queues for long time. All is banking requirements plus additional VALUE ADDED SERVICES can bring banking to his doorstep by a simple click of a mouse.

Assistant Project Manager at the Bank of Punjab

March 2014 - November 2016 (2 years 8 months)

Proven as multi-disciplined, management skills and a major player in numerous operations and projects and implemented and developed new systems with cost constraints and best available resources.

I'm truly passionate about helping teams understand customers better and creating products and services that plaster silly grins on customers' faces whenever they engage with traditional and alternative touchpoints. Have a diplomatic management style, whilst empowers, develops and encourages a self-development culture. Having diversified professional career, with more than 10years, I have worked in different areas and have grown myself along with the organization. Highly experienced in

- Mange Call Center Application and support.
- Business Continuity/Contingency Plan.
- Manage Call Center Data Center and connectivity
- Terminal Services
- VMWare Infrastructure
- Create Clustering environment in banking environment
- DR & BCP
- Centralized Event Logs & Proactive Monitoring
- Application Support

Call Center Application and Server

Mange call center application, Database and test server as deployed on windows server 2008 R2 with clustering environment.

IVR Interact 5

Mange IVR (Interact 5) server and application as deployed on Linux and windows based environment.

Call center Data center.

¬Mange Call center data center including connectivity backup link and all call center system policy server and MacAfee antivirus.

System Administrator at NIB Bank

January 2008 - March 2014 (6 years 2 months)

Equipped with relevant experience for providing Support in Banking Applications & Operations, major responsibilities include the following:

- Manage overall NIB Datacenter inside Datacenter more than 300 server running multiple application and database. Also responsible Disaster recovery site of the NIB bank. Maintaining and monitoring more than 300 branches servers' connectivity
- Live backup and high availability.
- Manage Active Directory services, User accouts, OU, Groups, policies.
- Performing Backup of all user's profile, head office / branches group data, virtual machines, call center recording, production backup.
- Managing LTO4 tape library and backup media tapes at head office and DR site.
- Backup Images of servers and restoration of backup with the help Acronis True Image.
- Maintains and Troubleshoot Microsoft Exchange Server.
- Maintains and troubleshoot MacAfee Antivirus 8.5 Solution.
- Head Office and DR Site Data Center maintenance and troubleshooting.
- Provide Technical Support to NIB users all over Pakistan.
- Installation of Servers, antivirus, hardware, drivers, tools and patches to the systems
- Maintenance of mail-server & managing user accounts on email server and support email users
- 24/7 Monitoring of Servers existing HO and DR site Data Center.

System Support Officer at PICIC BANK

February 2007 - December 2007 (10 months)

- Software Quality assurance testing for new Banking updates and modules.
- To Run the Start of End & Day End Operations of PIBAS.
- Installations of PIBAS at Servers & Clients.
- Provide technical support to Branch users.
- To take routine backups as defined in the Bank Policy.
- To update the patches received from the Head Office.
- A part of my responsibilities I was involved in Foreign Exchange & Branch Operations.

• To co-ordinate with other departments in respect of various matters

Education

YEAR

Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Political Science and Government, 2004 - 2006

BCIT

Bachelor's degree, COMPUTER INFORMATION & TECHNOLOGY; POLITICAL SCIENCE, 2002 - 2006

Syed Muhammad Nouman

Team Lead & Senior Project Manager

syed_syed786@hotmail.com

Linked III.

https://www.linkedin.com/in/syed-muhammad-nouman-86b33723/

Contact Syed Muhammad on LinkedIn